fotolia.com 2018-09-04

# Fotolia - Royalty-free licenses and other agreements from our image bank

This Privacy Policy, as amended from time to time (the "Policy"), describes how Fotolia LLC, a wholly owned subsidiary of Adobe, collects, uses and shares information about you when you visit or use the [Fotolia.com](https://us.fotolia.com/ "Fotolia.com") website and services or otherwise interact with us. It also describes your data protection rights, which may include a right to object to some of the processing which Fotolia carries out. 

**Summary of Key Points**

  * **Where your consent is required, we will obtain your permission as described below, such as before sending you news and promotional material about Fotolia. You can withdraw your consent to such activities at any time.Learn more. **
  * **This policy explains when we process personal information for our legitimate interests. You can ask us to stop processing this information.Learn more about your rights and how you can exercise them. **
  * We use your personal information to enable you to register with Fotolia and to provide you with our websites, and other products or services that you request. Learn more. 
  * We provide interactive features that engage with social media sites, such as Facebook. If you use these features, these sites will send us personal information about you. Learn more. 
  * We use cookies and other technologies to track the use of our websites and apps. To learn about opportunities to choose not to allow cookies, click [here](https://l3.evidon.com/site/414/6281/9). If you are using our Site in a browser, this information is also available in our [Cookies Policy](https://us.fotolia.com/Info/Agreements/PrivacyPolicy). 
  * There are several places within Fotolia websites and services that allow you to post comments, upload content, or submit content which will be publicly available where you choose to participate in these activities. We also disclose personal information to other companies in the Adobe family and with advertising and sales partners consistent with your choices. We also share information with third parties we engage to process information on our behalf or when such sharing is required by law, or in certain other situations. Learn more. 
  * We transfer your personal information to the US and other countries, which may be outside the country in which you live. We use European Commission approved contract clauses to help protect your personal information. Learn more. 

##  1\. Information Collection  Top 

###  What information does Fotolia collect about me? 

**Fotolia registration and customer support**

When you register with Fotolia or contact us for support or other offerings, we collect the information that you submit such as: 

  * Contact information such as your name, address, email address, telephone number; 
  * Preferred display name; 
  * Civility; 
  * Company name; 
  * VAT number; 
  * Billing address; 
  * Payment method; 
  * Communications with Fotolia support; 
  * Gallery names; 
  * Project names (on invoices); and 
  * Comments and content you post (for example, on our Blog) 

If you submit content to Fotolia for licensing, we may also require verification of your identity with a government issued ID and your tax forms, such as IRS Forms W-8 or W-9 required for tax purposes, and other information such as: 

  * Contact information such as your name, address, email address, telephone number; 
  * Payout email address; 
  * Content metadata; 
  * SSN / EIN 

For Partners (as identified on our Website), registration information may also include: 

  * API URL and Description; 

Fotolia also collects and tracks copyright infringement claims through its membership management module. 

**Fotolia website**

When you visit our Website, we may automatically collect certain information such as: 

  * Internet Protocol ("IP") address; 
  * Browser type; 
  * Operating system; 
  * Uploads and downloads on our website; 
  * Profile changes; 
  * Content changes; and 
  * Payment events 

**Models and Property Releases**

Fotolia receives Model Release Forms or Property Release Forms (as applicable) from its Contributors and will process the information in those forms including name, contact information and basic demographics for the purposes of licensing, defending legal claims, and protecting your rights. 

**Fotolia emails**

Emails we send you may include a technology (called a web beacon) that tells Fotolia whether you have received or opened the email, or clicked a link in the email. If you do not want us to collect this information from Fotolia marketing emails, you can opt out of receiving Fotolia marketing emails. 

**Fotolia online advertising**

Fotolia advertises online in a variety of ways, including displaying Fotolia ads to you on other companies' websites and apps. We collect information such as: 

  * Which ads are displayed; 
  * Which ads are clicked on; and 
  * Where the ad was displayed. 

**Buttons, tools, and content from other companies**

Fotolia services may include buttons, tools, or content that link to other companies’ services (for example, a Facebook "Like" button). We may collect information about your use of these features. This information may be used by Fotolia and others to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests on our services and other websites and apps and better understand your online activity. For more information about interest-based ads, or to opt out of having your web browsing information used for behavioral advertising purposes, please click [here](https://l3.evidon.com/site/414/6281/9). In addition, when you see or interact with these buttons, tools, or content, or view a Fotolia web page containing them, some information from your browser may automatically be sent to the other company. Please read that company’s privacy policy for more information. 

**Fotolia social networking pages**

Fotolia has its own pages on many social networking sites, such as Facebook. Where you give appropriate permissions, we will receive information about you when you interact with our social networking pages, such as name, location, basic demographic information. 

###  What are cookies and how does Fotolia use them? 

As with most websites, Fotolia and its partners use cookies, web beacons, and other technologies to collect information about users’ activities to make our website work as well as to learn more about our users. 

"Cookies" are small text files stored by your web browser when you use websites. Cookies and similar technologies help us improve our services and your experience, see which areas and features of our services are popular, and count visits. The type of information a cookie collects includes the date and time you visited, your browsing history, your preferences, and your username. 

Web beacons are bits of programming code that may be included in our webpages or emails and help deliver cookies, count visits, and understand usage and campaign effectiveness. 

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject cookies. Note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of our services. 

###  How does Fotolia use the information it collects about me, and what is the legal basis for this use? 

Fotolia uses the information we collect about you for the following purposes: 

  * To fulfil a contract, or take steps linked to a contract: this is relevant where you register to use the Fotolia service. This includes: 
    * Verifying your identity; 
    * Taking payments; 
    * Sending you necessary communications (for example, related to payments or expiration of your subscription); 
    * Providing you with the Fotolia products and services for which you have registered and any other services or products that you have requested; 
    * Providing customer services or support; and 
    * If you are a contributor, to compensate you and prepare your tax forms. 
  * As required by Fotolia to conduct our business and pursue our legitimate interests, in particular: 
    * Analyzing your use and measuring effectiveness of our website and services and interaction with our communications, to tailor and customize our website or services, and marketing communications so we can improve them and engage and retain users; 
    * Diagnosing problems in our website 
    * Personalizing a website, for you 
    * Sending you business messages such as those related to payments or expiration of your subscription 
    * Conducting surveys and market research about our customers, their interests, the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns, and customer satisfaction (unless we need consent to undertake such surveys, in which case we will only do this with your permission) 
    * Reducing piracy and copyright, and protecting you as well as Fotolia 
    * Facilitating your participation in our interactive features such as Blogs; 
    * Providing products and services you have requested, and respond to any comments or complaints you may send us 
    * Investigating and responding to any comments or complaints received from you or from others, about our website 
    * in connection with legal claims, e.g. copyright claims, compliance, regulatory and investigative purposes as necessary (including disclosure of information in connection with legal process or litigation) 
    * Sending you information about Fotolia, new releases, special offers, and similar information, and sharing your information with third parties for their marketing purposes (where your consent is not required) 
    * Detect, investigate, and prevent fraudulent and illegal activities and protect the rights and property of Fotolia and others 
  * Where you give Fotolia your consent or otherwise consistent with your choices: 
    * Sending you information about Fotolia, new releases, special offers, and similar information, and sharing your information with third parties for their own marketing purposes (where your consent is required) 
    * Placing cookies and using similar technologies on our website or services and in email communications, in accordance with our Cookies Policy and the information provided to you when those technologies are used. 
    * Running online campaigns and displaying Fotolia ads based on your likely interests. 

On other occasions where we ask you for consent, we will use the data for the purposes which we explain at that time. 

  * For legal reasons: 
    * Responding to requests by government or law enforcement authorities conducting an investigation. 

##  3\. Information Sharing  Top 

###  Does Fotolia share my personal information? 

**Sharing with Data Controllers**

We will share your personal data between and among Fotolia, the Adobe family of companies and our current and future family of companies for the purposes identified above (see a list of [Adobe entities](https://www.adobe.com/about-adobe/contact/offices.html) and our [acquired companies](https://www.adobe.com/privacy/policies.html)). The types of third parties your information may be shared with include, our resellers and other sales and advertising partners, retailers, research organizations, advertisers, ad agencies, advertising networks and platforms, information service providers, publishers, and non-profit organizations (with your consent, if required). 

**Sharing with Data Processors**

We will also share your personal data with companies that help us to run our business by processing personal data on behalf of Fotolia for the purposes identified above. Such companies include payment processing services, fraud monitoring and prevention, email, social media, and other marketing platforms and service providers, and hosting services. 

Fotolia may also share your personal information: 

  * When you agreed to the sharing 
  * When we are required to provide information in response to a subpoena, court order, or other applicable law or legal process 
  * When we have a good faith belief that the disclosure is necessary to prevent or respond to fraud, defend our apps or websites against attacks, or protect the property and safety of Fotolia, our customers and users, or the public 
  * If we merge with or are acquired by another company, sell our website, or business unit, or if all or a substantial portion of our assets are acquired by another company, your information will likely be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchaser's advisers and will be one of the assets that is transferred to the new owner. 
  * We may share or publish aggregate information that doesn’t specifically identify you, such as statistical information about visitors to our websites or statistical information about how customers use our products. 

###  Is my personal data displayed anywhere on Fotolia's websites? 

As a registered user of Fotolia, you may participate in Fotolia’s Blog. Blog postings are visible to any guest of our website. Please be careful when you share your personal information. Do not share anything you wouldn’t want publicly known unless you are sure you are posting it within an app or website that allows you to control who sees what you post. Please note that when you post messages on certain places on our websites and services your selected alias be included and displayed with your message. Messages posted to the Blog may be retained so long as the Fotolia website is operational. 

As a contributor to Fotolia, we will display your first and last name or the preferred name that you choose, on our website in connection with selling licenses for your content including but not limited to displaying your name by your content, in the metadata of your content (if a customer downloads it) and in the shopping cart. 

We understand that the security of your personal information is important. We provide reasonable administrative, technical, and physical security controls to protect your personal information. However, despite our efforts, no security controls are 100% effective and Fotolia cannot ensure or warrant the security of your personal information. 

##  5\. Transfer of Information to the U.S. and Other Countries  Top 

We may transfer your personal information across national borders to other countries in compliance with applicable laws. 

Where Fotolia transfers your personal information from the EEA to a country which is not within the EEA and is not subject to an adequacy decision by the EU Commission, we rely on one or more of the following legal mechanisms: EU Commission approved Standard Contractual Clauses, a vendor's binding corporate rules, and your consent. A copy of the relevant mechanism can be provided for your review upon request, using the contact details provided at the end of this Privacy Policy. 

Where provided by applicable law, you have the right to ask us for a copy of your personal data; to correct, delete or restrict (stop any active) processing of your personal data; and to obtain the personal data you provide to us for a contract or with your consent in a structured, machine readable format, and to ask us to share (port) this data to another controller. Wherever we rely on your consent, you will always be able to withdraw that consent, although we may have other legal grounds for processing your data for other purposes, such as those set out above. 

In addition, you can object to the processing of your personal data in some circumstances (in particular, where we don’t have to process the data to meet a contractual or other legal requirement, or where we are using the data for direct marketing). 

These rights may be limited, for example if fulfilling your request would reveal personal data about another person, or if you ask us to delete information which we are required by law to keep or have compelling legitimate interests in keeping (such as fraud prevention purposes, to defend claims, or protect legal rights). 

You may review or change the information you provide to us by going to the "My Profile" section of the Website. If you wish to delete your information or deactivate your account, contact us via telephone or the “Contact Us” form on the Website. 

To exercise any of these rights (including deactivating your Fotolia account), you can get in touch with us using the details set out below. If you have unresolved concerns, you have the right to complain to an EU data protection authority where you live, work or where you believe a breach may have occurred. 

To register with Fotolia, to create an Fotolia account, and to use the Fotolia website, products or services, the provision of some information is mandatory: if relevant information is not provided, then we will not be able to administer a Fotolia account to you, or provide you with the websites, apps, products or services requested. All other provision of your information is optional. Providing optional information will help us offer you a better experience, such as more personalized or tailored content or offerings. 

###  Withdrawing consent or otherwise objecting to direct marketing? 

We and companies we hire to help us market our websites and apps on our behalf may use your information to provide you with information and offers related to Fotolia. 

Wherever we rely on your consent, you will always be able to withdraw that consent, although we may have other legal grounds for processing your information for other purposes, such as those set out above. In some cases, we are able to send you direct marketing without your consent, where we rely on our legitimate interests. You have an absolute right to opt-out of direct marketing, or profiling we carry out for direct marketing, at any time by: 

  * updating your preferences in the "My Profile" section of the Website; or 
  * by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our marketing emails; 
  * contacting us using the details provided at the end of this privacy policy. 

By opting out, you will no longer receive certain special offers or promotions, but we may continue to send you non-promotional communications, such as those about your account or our ongoing business relations. 

Click [here](https://us.fotolia.com/Member/Modify/Preferences "My Preferences") for further information on your choices regarding our marketing practices. 

###  How long will you retain my data? 

Where we process registration data, we do this for as long as you are an active user of our websites, apps or products. When you close your account, we delete certain personal information that we no longer have a business reason to retain, such as your hashed password and your payment account data. However, we typically retain personal information related to our contract and business transactions with you for seven years after your last interaction with us. Where you have perpetually licensed content to us – or have perpetually licensed content from us – we need to keep a record of that in perpetuity for license and royalty management purposes. Model and property releases also are kept in perpetuity (as certain content rights are perpetual) for licensing the content, investigating, preventing legal claims, and to protect third party rights. We also keep our contributor’s bank details so we can verify that Fotolia paid the contributors for the licenses that Fotolia sold. 

Where we process personal data for marketing purposes or with your consent, we process the data until you ask us to stop and for a short period after this (to allow us to implement your requests). We also keep a permanent record of the fact that you have asked us not to send you direct marketing or to process your data so that we can respect your request in future. 

##  8\. Notification of Changes  Top 

Occasionally, we may change this privacy policy (to allow Fotolia to use or share your personal information in a different way. If we do, the links to the policy on our websites (which are generally found in the footer of the website) will be updated and we will notify you by revising the "last updated date" at the top of this Policy and highlighting this on the Website. For new users, the change will become effective upon posting. For existing users, if the change is significant, it will become effective 30 days after posting. We encourage you to periodically review the Privacy Policy for the latest information on our privacy practices. 

###  Who can I contact with questions or concerns? 

If you have a privacy question, concern or request, please contact us [here](http://www.adobe.com/go/privacyinquiry "Privacy Inquiry"). You can also get in touch with Fotolia by writing to 345 Park Avenue, San Jose, CA 95110.
